这是资阳市二零二一年
初中学业水平考试，即高中阶段教育学校招生统一考试，英语听力。
理解部分，该部分分为第一、第二两节。
注意，回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间
将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。
Please of comprehension part.
请看听力理解部分第一节。
第一节，听下面五段对话，
每段对话后有一个小题。
从题中所给的
three A, B and Text 1.
一，三个选项中，选出与其意思相符的图片，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听每段对话前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，
每小题五秒钟。
听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟。
的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题，
每段对话仅读一遍。
现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读第一小题的有关内容。
this Mike's history book?
No, it's mine.
The math book on the desk is his.
Text 2. Are you in New York?
hear it is snowing heavily there.
No, I'm not.
I cancelled my trip because my mother was ill.
Text 3. Andy, do your family like drinking tea?
Only my father likes it.
My mother and I like drinking coffee.
Text 4. did you tell your mother about the good news?
By sending a short message.
Text 5. I like dogs very much.
They are so lovely.
I want to keep one as a pet.
Really? of. for section.
但我觉得猫更容易照顾。
第一节到此结束。
第二节，听下。
下面五段对话或独白，
每段对话或独白后有几个小题。
从题中所给的
B and questions.
三个选项中选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听每段对话或独白前。
你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听下面一段对话。
回答第六至第七小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题
Okay. How about the tie?
It's nice. But the blue shirt is better.
How much is it?
It's sixty dollars.
Okay. I'll take it.
Here is the money.
Thank you. Good afternoon.
Can I help you?
I'm looking for a Father's Day gift.
Okay. How about the tie?
It's nice. But the blue shirt is better.
How much is it?
It's sixty dollars.
Okay. I'll take it.
Here is the money.
Thank you. answer Okay.
听下面一段对话，回答
第八至第十小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
I'll 7 Li Qiang, do you like music?
Yes, I do.
And I like traditional Chinese music.
Then can you play the arhu?
Yes, but I can't play well.
My father is good at it.
He often teaches me.
Is your father a teacher or an actor?
No, he is a policeman.
When he is free, he studies Chinese music.
Oh, I hear there is a music festival in our school next Thursday.
I see. I want to take part in it then.
8 Li Qiang, do you like music?
Yes, I do.
And I like traditional Chinese music.
Then can you play the arhu?
Yes, but I can't play well.
My father is good at it.
He often teaches me.
Is your father a teacher or an actor?
No, he is a policeman.
When he is free, he studies Chinese music.
Oh, I hear there is a music festival in our school next Thursday.
I see. I want to take part in it then.
Text 9 Text 8 You are late again.
听下面一段对话，回答
第十一至第十。
单小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
The film has been on for 15 minutes.
I'm really sorry.
The bus was late.
Why didn't you drive your car?
I sold my car yesterday.
Really? But why?
I think it's our duty to care for our environment.
You have changed a lot.
I joined a volunteer club named Green Helper last month.
It's time to take action to protect our environment.
I quite agree with you.
We should try to live a green life.
You are late again.
The film has been on for 15 minutes.
I'm really sorry.
The bus was late.
Why didn't you drive your car?
I sold my car yesterday.
Really? But why?
I think it's our duty to care for our environment.
You have changed a lot.
I joined a volunteer club named Green Helper last month.
It's time to take action to protect our environment.
I quite agree with you.
We should try to live a green life.
听下面一段对话，回答
第十四至第十六小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
What do you want to do, Rose?
I want to go to the museum.
There is a science show for children.
That sounds interesting.
Would you like to go with me?
Yes, I'd love to.
Great! I'm sure we'll have a great time.
Could I take a camera with me?
I want to take some photos.
I'm afraid you can't.
We are not allowed to take photos inside the museum.
Got it. Oh, where shall we meet?
At the gate of the museum.
Be sure to get there before 9 o And you can take number 5 bus.
It can take you right there.
Okay. See you then.
Hi, Peter. The examination is over.
What are you going to do tomorrow?
I'm not sure.
What do you want to do, Rose?
I want to go to the museum.
There is a science show for children.
That sounds interesting.
Would you like to go with me?
Yes, I'd love to.
Great! Could I take a camera with me?
I want to take some photos.
I'm afraid you can't.
We are not allowed to take photos inside the museum.
Got it. Oh, where shall we meet?
At the gate of the museum.
Be sure to get there before 9 o And you can take number 5 bus.
It can Okay.
See you then.
听。
下面一段独白，回答第十七至第二十小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间
阅读这四个小题。
Text 10. Hi, class.
I know you like Chinese tea culture.
So we'll go on a trip to a tea garden this Sunday.
We'll meet at the school library at 8 o 'clock and set out at 8.30.
There will be two buses waiting for us.
Those whose student number is from 1 to 20 will take the number 1 bus.
The other 21 students will take the number 2 bus.
After we arrive at the tea garden,
please be quiet and don't touch the tea trees if not allowed.
Mr. the owner of the garden, will show us around the garden and teach us how to pick
and fry tea leaves.
Hope you'll like the tea garden and Chinese tea culture.
Hi, class. I know you like Chinese tea culture.
So we'll go on a trip to a tea garden this Sunday.
We'll meet at the school library at 8 o and set out at 8.30.
There will be two buses waiting for us.
Those whose student number is from 1 to 20 will take the number 1 bus.
The other 21 students will take the number 2 bus.
After we arrive at the tea garden, please be quiet and don't touch the tea trees if
not allowed. Mr.
the owner of the garden, will show us around the garden and teach us how to pick and
fry tea leaves.
Hope you'll like the tea garden and Chinese tea culture.
The Thank you.
第二节到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间。
将试卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
you. Thank you.
听力理解部分到此结束
Thank you. Thank you.